<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | </title>
    <link>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/media/icon_hu56437e0029043a6980b2632a303bfe7c_22443_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>causalBETA</title>
      <link>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/causalbeta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/causalbeta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborative Causal and Bayesian Modeling</title>
      <link>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/applied/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/applied/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of some applied work with particularly interesting Bayesian and/or causal modeling. For instance, Hubbard et al. use a Bayesian mixture model to infer patients&#39; unknown diabetes status in noisy EHR data. Harrison et al. use a Bayesian hierarchical zero-inflated model to assess difference in costs associated with a cost-lowering healthcare intervention. Takvorian et al. use a difference-in-differences strategy to assess the impact of medicare expansion under ACA on cancer treatment delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-parametric Bayes</title>
      <link>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/bnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/bnp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bayesian nonparametrics is a powerful class of methods including Gaussian processes, Bayesian Additive Regression Trees (BART), Gamma Processes, Dirichlet Process, etc. The central idea is to abstract away from parameters. For instance, standard methods may assume a regression function is linear, indexed by finitely many slope/intercept parameters. A prior on these finitely many parameters then induces a prior on the regression function. To avoid specifying such restrictive functional form, we need to cut out the middle-man (the parameters) and specify priors over the function &lt;em&gt;directly&lt;/em&gt;. Bayesian nonparametrics is characterized by priors over such abstract objects: priors over regressions, priors over baseline hazard functions, prior distributions over distributions themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These methods give you the flexibility of machine learning, with the added benefit uncertainty quantitification via full posterior inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See below for work related to nonparametric Bayesian inference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/causalbayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/causalbayes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Causal inference is broadly concerned with estimating parameters governing the causal mechanisms between an intervention or treatment of interest and an outcome. Causal inference provides a framework for 1) constructing different estimands that have explicitly causal, rather than associational, interpretations 2) formulating the assumptions under which we can estimate these using observed data, 3) devising sensitivity analyses around violations of these assumptions, and 4) making valid inferences about these estimans. These are just some of the many advances made in the causal literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, causal inference requires complex, high-dimensional models. Here, the Bayesian paradigm has a lot to offer. For instance,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shrinking&lt;/strong&gt; heterogeneous (stratum-specific) causal effects towards an overall average causal effect for sparse strata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparsity priors&lt;/strong&gt; such as Horseshoes and Spike-and-Slab that can regularize high-dimensional nuissance parameters. Such parameters are common in g-computation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sensitivity Analyses&lt;/strong&gt; around causal identification assumptions. Uncertainty about the direction and magnitude of the bias can be expressed via a prior and baked into posterior inference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See below for work related to Bayesian causal modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChiRP</title>
      <link>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/chirp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stablemarkets.netlify.app/project/chirp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
